<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>iNeed.to</title><link href="https://ineed.to/" rel="alternate"/><link href="https://ineed.to/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"/><id>https://ineed.to/</id><updated>2025-07-20T19:30:00-07:00</updated><subtitle>Seeking the wholeness of the integrated person. Technology - Martial Arts - Learning</subtitle><entry><title>Always Click and Entra ID</title><link href="https://ineed.to/always-click/" rel="alternate"/><published>2025-04-21T19:30:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-21T19:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Bitpusher</name></author><id>tag:ineed.to,2025-04-21:/always-click/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Yubikey and Entra ID sign-in annoyance mitigated with a Chrome extension&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;An annoyance born of Entra ID flow, SSO, and hardware tokens&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any online account you care about which is capable of supporting multi-factor or multi-step authentication should have those capabilities enabled - the added security is very much worth it. Even better, if any of your accounts support hardware tokens or passkeys it's a good idea to use them for yet greater security. Microsoft's M365 ecosystem, through their Entra ID authentication services, does support hardware tokens &lt;a href="https://yubico.com"&gt;such as Yubikeys&lt;/a&gt; and passkeys (though only through the Microsoft Authenticator app).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I have a Yubikey configured for authentication to a corporate M365 account. This corporate account is also used to access a number of other services through Entra ID SSO connections - when I need to access these other services the website makes an authentication request through the browser and it's passed to Windows where I'm prompted to use my hardware token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Website authentication prompt" src="./../images/article-alwaysclick-auth1.png" style="width: 543px; height: auto;"/&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Windows authentication prompt" src="./../images/article-alwaysclick-token.png" style="width: 565px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enter a pin, tap the token, and authenticate. So far, so good... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then this pops up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Entra ID - Stay signed in?" src="./../images/article-alwaysclick-auth2.png" style="width: 545px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Entra ID "Stay signed in?" prompt. It is supposed to make life easier by allowing you to reduce the frequency of sign-in prompts on your personal system. The problem is that when using SSO to authenticate to third-party services it is the third-party service which controls the duration of the session, and this prompt does nothing. Additionally, (for my tenant configuration, at least) &lt;em&gt;the "Don't show this again" option has no effect.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I frequently find myself working between several tabs/services, and one of the SSO'ed session expires. Since the authentication was through a passkey/token the page with the expired session (even if it is in the background) will trigger the Windows "Sign in with your passkey" popup, interrupting whatever I'm doing. That can't be helped, and using a token means the interruption is at least quick and easy to get through - enter pin and tap token. However, adding insult to injury, if after re-authenticating the expired session I forget to click over to the background tab that started the authentication flow and &lt;em&gt;click past the "Stay signed in?" prompt again&lt;/em&gt; the authentication flow will soon time out and when next I go back to that tab I'll have to go through the process all over again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Always Click in the Chrome Web Store" src="./../images/article-alwaysclick-failed.png" style="width: 524px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A partial solution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing can be done at the user level about the expiration of SSO sessions and triggered Windows authentication popups... but there is at least a way to make the authentication complete without having to click the background tab and hit no/yes on the "Stay signed in?" prompt every time - The Chrome extension &lt;a href="https://chromewebstore.google.com/detail/always-click/mcdcmdmbhleoeafjimeobmnchldapbpf"&gt;Always Click&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Always Click in the Chrome Web Store" src="./../images/article-alwaysclick-install.png" style="width: 1778px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This handy extension will auto-click an element on a web page when it loads based on the URL and CSS selector. To make it work on the M365/Entra ID "Stay signed in?" prompt &lt;a href="https://chromewebstore.google.com/detail/always-click/mcdcmdmbhleoeafjimeobmnchldapbpf"&gt;install the extension&lt;/a&gt;, go to the extension's options, and add two URLs to it's configuration:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;https://login.microsoftonline.com/M365-TENANT-ID/login&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;https://login.microsoftonline.com/common/login&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replace "M365-TENANT-ID" with your M365 tenant's GUID, which you will sometimes see in the URL bar when re-authenticating your account or can &lt;a href="https://entra.microsoft.com/#view/Microsoft_AAD_IAM/TenantOverview.ReactView"&gt;lookup here&lt;/a&gt;. For the CSS selector paste in "input#idBtn_Back.win-button.button-secondary.button.ext-button.secondary.ext-secondary" without quotes on both lines. Or you can &lt;a href="https://ineed.to/always-click/always-click-export.json"&gt;download and import this settings file&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Always Click settings" src="./../images/article-alwaysclick-settings.png" style="width: 1578px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this configuration in place whenever that maddening "Stay signed in?" popup appears the "No" button will be automatically clicked, and authentication completed. One less click for every Entra ID authentication flow, and several saved clicks for every re-authentication triggered by a background tab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walk on,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;Bitpusher
 \`._,'/
 (_- -_)
   \o/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Code"/><category term="article"/><category term="chrome"/><category term="extension"/><category term="alwaysclick"/><category term="m365"/><category term="yubikey"/><category term="token"/><category term="entraid"/><category term="addon"/></entry><entry><title>Excel Macro Set</title><link href="https://ineed.to/excel-macros/" rel="alternate"/><published>2024-05-20T19:30:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-02-20T19:30:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Bitpusher</name></author><id>tag:ineed.to,2024-05-20:/excel-macros/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Adding a few simple macros to the Excel ribbon can greatly enhance functionality &amp;amp; speed common tasks&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Spreadsheets - A killer app since 1979&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The macro ribbon" src="./../images/article-excelmacros-thejob.png" style="width: 1177px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm no Excel expert, but nonetheless find myself working with the magical grid nearly every day. Very often for my line of work that entails reviewing log files for suspicious activity, finding patterns, and preparing reports based on what I find. after doing the same steps over and over, I finally dug in, assembled a set of macros, and figured out how to add them to the Excel ribbon menu for easy access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My Excel Macro Ribbon Set&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The macro ribbon" src="./../images/article-excelmacros-intro.png" style="width: 1058px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can download the set of &lt;a href="https://github.com/bitpusher2k/ExcelMacros"&gt;ExcelMacros on GitHub here&lt;/a&gt; and follow the included instructions for adding them to your Excel ribbon. Full installation and configuration information is in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/bitpusher2k/ExcelMacros/blob/main/README.md"&gt;readme&lt;/a&gt;, and here is a description of what each macro/button in the current version can do for you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initialize CSV - Applies the next five macros in sequence - Handy for initializing a CSV log file for manual review.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auto Fit All Columns (50) - Auto-fits all column width with maximum with for each column of 50 characters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auto Fit All Rows (50) - Auto-fits all row height with maximum height for each row of 50 characters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add Filter - Adds filter to top row. I know this is easy enough to do with the Ctrl+Shift+L shortcut, but this fits in with the flow when using other related macros and the "Initialize CSV" above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide Empty Columns - Hides all columns which have data only in the first row (assumed to be the header row).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide GUID Columns - Hide all columns which have a GUID in the second row (the first is assumed to be the header).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Split Date And Time To New Columns - Use only if a column containing date-space-time is selected - Creates two new columns to the right, copies date into the first, and copies time into the second.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highlight Cells With Selected Value - Highlights all CELLS which contains the value in the currently selected cell. Can then use filter by color to limit view to highlighted entries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highlight Rows With Selected Value - Highlights all ROWS that have a cell which contains the value in the currently selected cell. &lt;em&gt;Separate macros for yellow/green/red highlighting included.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blank If Error - Surround formulas in all selected cells with =IFERROR(,"").&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convert Selected To Values - Converts formulas in selected cells to values.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highlight Duplicate Values Selected Range - Highlights duplicate values in the selected range of cells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save Worksheet As PDF - Saves current worksheet as a PDF of the same name in the same folder as the original without any further prompts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save Worksheet As XLSX - Saves current worksheet as XLSX with same path &amp;amp; filename as the original open file. Handy when processing CSV files - faster than pressing F12 &amp;gt; clicking Drop-down menu &amp;gt; clicking XLSX &amp;gt; clicking Save.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear All Highlighting - Clears all highlighting in the worksheet (in case highlighting went awry with previous macros).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unhide All Rows Columns - Un-hides all manually hidden columns (and rows, if no filters are applied).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CustomSort - Brings up the custom sort dialog (saves a couple clicks).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete Hidden Rows - Deletes all currently hidden rows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DeleteH idden Columns - Deletes all currently hidden columns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The macro ribbon in action" src="./../images/article-excelmacros-excel.png" style="width: 2333px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Caveat Emptor: These macros are not particularly refined - no error handling, and some edge cases will cause them to fail - but they're good enough to save me a lot of time daily, so they're about as good as they're going to get for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Additional Excel tips&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you, like me, tend to have multiple spreadsheets open I recommend updating the Registry so that when opening a sheet/CSV by double-clicking it opens Excel in Embedded mode (prevents the default workbook Book.xltx from being created and startup screen from appearing) and opens each sheet/CSV in its own instance of the "Excel.exe" app so that if an operation (function, macro) is fully occupying one instance all of them are not frozen (you can go work on another sheet until the macro finishes). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The changes needed are at least updating "Excel.CSV" and "Excel.Sheet.12":&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HKEY_CLASSES_ROOT\Excel.Sheet.12\shell\Open\command to "\"C:\Program Files\Microsoft Office\Root\Office16\EXCEL.EXE\" /e \"%1\" /o \"%u\""&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HKEY_CLASSES_ROOT\Excel.CSV\shell\Open\command to "\"C:\Program Files\Microsoft Office\Root\Office16\EXCEL.EXE\" /e \"%1\" /o \"%u\""&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Read-only" src="./../images/article-excelmacros-reg.png" style="width: 1267px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are two REG files that can be imported to update these values: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://ineed.to/excel-macros/ExcelCSVopenwithoutotherpopup.reg"&gt;ExcelCSVopenwithoutotherpopup.reg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://ineed.to/excel-macros/ExcelSheetopenwithoutotherpopup.reg"&gt;ExcelSheetopenwithoutotherpopup.reg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then go to %appdata%\Microsoft\Excel\XLSTART, right-click PERSONAL.XLSB and set the file attributes to read-only to prevent a "file in use" popup when multiple instances of Excel are started and each reads the macro file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Read-only" src="./../images/article-excelmacros-readonly.png" style="width: 526px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walk on,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;Bitpusher
 \`._,'/
 (_- -_)
   \o/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Code"/><category term="article"/><category term="excel"/><category term="macro"/><category term="logs"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="incident"/><category term="response"/><category term="ribbon"/></entry><entry><title>JKD Resources</title><link href="https://ineed.to/learn-jkd/" rel="alternate"/><published>2024-03-30T16:40:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-07-20T19:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Bitpusher</name></author><id>tag:ineed.to,2024-03-30:/learn-jkd/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Online resources for the martial art of Jeet Kune Do&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Header" src="./../images/fight-header.png" style="width: 1000px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Jeet Kune Do resources to learn from on the web&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Longstreet Episode 1 - Way of the Intercepting Fist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=" position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;
&lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1_C6wKGL_ug" style="border: 1; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" title="Longstreet Episode 1 - Way of the Intercepting Fist (Bruce Lee)"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Return of the Dragon - Colosseum fight scene&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=" position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;
&lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kmgcqOM9rG0" style="border: 1; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" title="Bruce Lee vs Chuck Norris - The Way of the Dragon (Return of the Dragon)"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://jkdwednite.com/"&gt;The Wednesday Night Group - Original JKD passed on through one of the original groups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@jkdwng"&gt;JKD Wednesday Night Group YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@jeremylynch8923"&gt;Jeet Kune Do Senior Instructor Jeremy Lynch's YouTube channel (with WNG podcast)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ineed.to/learn-jkd/JeremyLynch-OneInchOfPower.pdf"&gt;One Inch of Power - PDF eBook of exercises to improve the one inch punch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ineed.to/learn-jkd/JeremyLynch-JeetKuneDoBasics.pdf"&gt;Jeet Kune Do Basics - PDF eBook several fundamental JKD techniques&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walk on,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt; \`._,'/
 (_- -_)
   \o/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="fight"/><category term="article"/><category term="jkd"/><category term="resources"/><category term="longstreet"/><category term="punch"/><category term="ebook"/><category term="pdf"/><category term="download"/><category term="grow"/><category term="basics"/></entry><entry><title>Everything Launcher</title><link href="https://ineed.to/everything-launcher/" rel="alternate"/><published>2024-02-23T16:40:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-02-23T16:40:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Bitpusher</name></author><id>tag:ineed.to,2024-02-23:/everything-launcher/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Consider using a fast search tool as your launcher - better than Spotlight/PowerToys Run/Launchy/etc.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Accidentally using a search tool as a launcher&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long before PowerToys Run was a thing I accidentally began using the &lt;a href="https://www.voidtools.com/"&gt;search program Everything by Voidtools&lt;/a&gt; as a launcher... and it worked out so well I'm not going to stop any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don't know about Everything, it's a lightning-fast search utility that instantly became one of the first tools I install on any new system after I discovered it (I think through its inclusion on ninite.com). Despite the great improvements to the built-in Windows search in the past decade it still can't touch the performance of good third-party tools, and the desire to have quality search at my fingertips lead me to tie opening the Everything utility to the shortcut Ctrl+Win+A using an &lt;a href="https://github.com/bitpusher2k/AHKscripts"&gt;AutoHotKeys macro&lt;/a&gt;. After that, I found myself naturally using it to locate and run programs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Searching for a program with Everything" src="./../images/article-everythinglauncher-search.png" style="width: 1077px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Everything is so handy and can locate bat scripts, portable executables, and other odd apps &amp;amp; utilities that I store in unconventional locations instantly it functions as the best launcher I've ever used - and without barely any configuration or customization. I'd strongly recommend trying it - fantastic as a search tool, and if you like to keep you hands on the keyboard and have rapid access to all programs/scripts on your system (wherever they may be) it could work great as a launcher for you, too. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install Everything using WinGet by running &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;winget install -e --id voidtools.Everything&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.voidtools.com/downloads/"&gt;Download installer/portable version at https://www.voidtools.com/downloads/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd recommend the Alpha 1.5 version (mainly due to the addition of a dark theme)...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WinGet install: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;winget install -e --id=voidtools.Everything.Alpha&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.voidtools.com/everything-1.5a/"&gt;Download installer/portable version at https://www.voidtools.com/everything-1.5a/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.voidtools.com/support/everything/searching/"&gt;Learn about the search operators at https://www.voidtools.com/support/everything/searching/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default settings are decent - The only areas I'd recommend reviewing at the outset are what drives are being indexed under Tools &amp;gt; Options &amp;gt; Indexes, and enabling searching the entire path of a file under Search &amp;gt; Match Path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Searching the entire path of files with Everything" src="./../images/article-everythinglauncher-pathsearch.png" style="width: 522px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walk on,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;Bitpusher
 \`._,'/
 (_- -_)
   \o/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Code"/><category term="article"/><category term="tips"/><category term="voidtools"/><category term="everything"/><category term="search"/><category term="launcher"/><category term="utility"/></entry><entry><title>Windows Terminal Customization</title><link href="https://ineed.to/terminal-customize/" rel="alternate"/><published>2024-01-30T16:40:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-07-19T22:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Bitpusher</name></author><id>tag:ineed.to,2024-01-30:/terminal-customize/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Enhance your Windows terminal experience to make PowerShell easier to use and learn&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Enhancing the Windows PowerShell experience&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Windows Terminal" src="./../images/article-terminalcustomization-top.png" style="width: 1195px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best tool is the one you have at hand (given that it is reasonably capable of doing the job, anyway), and since some version of PowerShell is natively installed on well over 90% of the systems I need to work on these days, PowerShell proficiency is a very attractive thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To improve my local PowerShell interactions I've customized the Windows terminal a bit. Customizations are based on &lt;a href="https://www.hanselman.com/blog/how-to-make-a-pretty-prompt-in-windows-terminal-with-powerline-nerd-fonts-cascadia-code-wsl-and-ohmyposh"&gt;those described by Scott Hanselman here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Windows Terminal customization steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="(https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/terminal/install)"&gt;Install Windows Terminal&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/package-manager/winget/"&gt;WinGet&lt;/a&gt; if they are not already installed (they are by default in Windows 11)]
    (All below code blocks assume they are being entered in a Windows Terminal PowerShell window)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/powershell/scripting/install/installing-powershell-on-windows?view=powershell-7.4"&gt;Install PowerShell 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;winget search Microsoft.PowerShell&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;winget install --id Microsoft.Powershell --source winget&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Install a nice console font that includes ligatures &amp;amp; hieroglyphs - CaskaydiaCove NF recommended but &lt;a href="https://www.nerdfonts.com/font-downloads"&gt;any overkill Nerd Font will work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/ryanoasis/nerd-fonts/releases/download/v3.4.0/CascadiaCode.zip"&gt;Download CaskaydiaCove Nerd Font&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; extract all TTF fonts to to c:\windows\fonts
&lt;code&gt;Invoke-WebRequest "https://github.com/ryanoasis/nerd-fonts/releases/download/v3.4.0/CascadiaCode.zip" -Out CascadiaCode.zip&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$zip = [IO.Compression.ZipFile]::OpenRead("$($PWD.path)\CascadiaCode.zip")&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$entries = $zip.Entries | where {$_.FullName -like '*.ttf'}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$entries | foreach {[IO.Compression.ZipFileExtensions]::ExtractToFile( $_, "c:\Windows\fonts\" + $_.Name)}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$zip.Dispose()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/gerardog/gsudo"&gt;Install gsudo (for prompt elevation option)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;winget install -e --id gerardog.gsudo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize Windows Terminal settings and add 'Admin' terminal profiles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. From Windows Terminal pull down menu and select 'Settings'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Select PowerShell profile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. Under 'Appearance' switch profile font to installed Nerd Font
&lt;img alt="Windows Terminal settings" src="./../images/article-terminalcustomization-settings.png" style="width: 1714px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. Select "Add new profile" &amp;gt; Duplicate the profile above&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;e. Customize the new profile to run as administrator, and rename with "(admin)" in the title
&lt;img alt="Windows Terminal menu" src="./../images/article-terminalcustomization-runasadmin.png" style="width: 1086px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;f. Repeat this for each of the PowerShell 5, PowerShell 7, and CMD profiles - you should end up with menu options for PS5, PS7, CMD, and admin versions of each
&lt;img alt="Windows Terminal menu" src="./../images/article-terminalcustomization-menu.png" style="width: 891px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start a PowerShell 7 session and &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/powershell/gallery/powershellget/"&gt;install PowerShellGet if not already installed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Install-Module PowerShellGet -Force&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close all open Windows Terminal windows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ohmyposh.dev/docs/installation/windows"&gt;Start a PowerShell 7 session and install Oh-my-posh (terminal theme engine)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;winget install --id JanDeDobbeleer.OhMyPosh --source winget&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/PowerShell/PSReadLine"&gt;Install PSReadLine (syntax coloring, handle multi-line, history, etc.)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Install-Module -Name PSReadLine -AllowPrerelease -Scope CurrentUser -Force -SkipPublisherCheck&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/devblackops/Terminal-Icons"&gt;Install terminal icons (show file/folder icons in terminal)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Install-Module -Name Terminal-Icons -Repository PSGallery&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update profile for PowerShell 7 to start with customizations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a. Open PS 7 window&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;b. Run "notepad $PROFILE"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;c. Allow notepad to create a new file if it does not already exist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;d. Add the following lines to the end of the file and save:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;oh&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;my&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;posh&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;init&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;pwsh&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;--config "$env:POSH_THEMES_PATH\jandedobbeleer.omp.json" | Invoke-Expression # Start Oh My Posh with JanDeDobbeleer theme&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Import&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;Module&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;PSReadLine&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;Start&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;PSReadLine&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;module&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ow"&gt;and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;up&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;options&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;below&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;Set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;PSReadLineOption&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;PredictionSource&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;History&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;Set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;PSReadLineOption&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;PredictionViewStyle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;ListView&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;Set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;PSReadLineOption&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;EditMode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Windows&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Import&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;Module&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Terminal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Icons&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nl"&gt;env&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;POWERSHELL_TELEMETRY_OPTOUT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Opt&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;out&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;sending&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;telemetry&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Microsoft&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nl"&gt;https&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;//&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;learn&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;microsoft&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;en&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;us&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;powershell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;module&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;microsoft&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;powershell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;core&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;about&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;about_telemetry&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="vm"&gt;?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;view&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;powershell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mf"&gt;7.5&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;Global&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;PSDefaultParameterValues&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;Add&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;"Out-Default:OutVariable"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;"__"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Results&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;of&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ow"&gt;all&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;commands&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;entered&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;will&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;up&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ow"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;__&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;variable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;Global&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;PSDefaultParameterValues&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;Add&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;"Update-Help:UICulture"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;cultureinfo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;]::&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;new&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ss"&gt;"en-US"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;Set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;UICulture&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;Update&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Help&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;clear&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close all open Windows Terminal windows &amp;amp; reopen one more time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DONE! Pin the 'Windows Terminal' to your task bar &amp;amp; enjoy easy access to an enhanced PowerShell experience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Windows Terminal menu" src="./../images/article-terminalcustomization-window.png" style="width: 1733px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the process see &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/terminal/tutorials/custom-prompt-setup"&gt;Microsoft's tutorial&lt;/a&gt; and Scott's video &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/VT2L1SXFq9U"&gt;How to make the ultimate Terminal Prompt on Windows 11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walk on,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;Bitpusher
 \`._,'/
 (_- -_)
   \o/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Code"/><category term="article"/><category term="windows"/><category term="terminal"/><category term="powershell"/><category term="customize"/><category term="psreadline"/><category term="nerdfont"/><category term="gsudo"/></entry><entry><title>Tune up your computer with recommended software</title><link href="https://ineed.to/tuneup/" rel="alternate"/><published>2023-03-30T16:40:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-20T19:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Bitpusher</name></author><id>tag:ineed.to,2023-03-30:/tuneup/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recommended software for a safe, secure, and productive PC&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Fox right" src="./../images/techtip.png" style="width: 450px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Tune up your computer with recommended software for a safe, secure, and productive PC&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Password management, MFA, &amp;amp; Passkeys&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bitwarden.com/"&gt;Bitwarden (free, or $10/year to add one-time key support)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://keepass.info/download.html"&gt;KeePass (free and open source)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;AV/EDR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/windows-security-app-overview-ae70cc96-a9cd-4443-a210-e41cb973d3a6"&gt;Windows Security App (built into Windows 10/11)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.malwarebytes.com/mwb-download/thankyou"&gt;Malwarebytes (free - will try to upsell you, but still decent)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Software patching&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/marticliment/UnigetUI/releases/latest/download/UniGetUI.Installer.exe"&gt;UniGetUI (free and open source)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Backup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/referrals/AADQRCBPXjGV4eKM1RSAtK64w3FrKxXQ0mI?src=global9"&gt;Dropbox (2gb free online sync/backup)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/my-drive"&gt;Google Drive (15gb storage with free google account - best photo backup &amp;amp; sharing)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://secure.backblaze.com/r/01c2ra"&gt;Backblaze&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://freefilesync.org/download.php"&gt;FreeFileSync (best for syncing files to external media manually)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://duplicati.com/download"&gt;Duplicati (local backup utility - free personal version)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.fbackup.com/fbackup.html"&gt;FBackup (free local backup utility)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Productivity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.firefox.com/en-US/?redirect_source=mozilla-org"&gt;Firefox (free and independent browser with great extensions)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sumatrapdfreader.org/free-pdf-reader"&gt;Sumatra PDF (free, small and lightning fast PDF/epub/mobi reader)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.videolan.org/vlc/"&gt;VLC (free and open source media player)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.7-zip.org/"&gt;7-Zip (free and open source archive file manager - zip, rar, cab, 7z, etc.)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.getpaint.net/index.html"&gt;Paint.NET (free image and photo editor)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Quick installer to get KeePass, Malwarebytes, Dropbox, Firefox, SumatraPDF, VLC, 7-zip, Everything, and Paint.NET installed all at once&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Ninite" src="https://ninite.com/static/img/brand-8a2e7c6ad769d6bc457c5c2b1a9743e8.png"/&gt;
&lt;a href="https://ninite.com/7zip-dropbox-everything-firefox-keepass2-malwarebytes-paint.net-sumatrapdf-vlc/ninite.exe"&gt;From Ninite.com - download &amp;amp; run&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;BONUS - Security Awareness&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.knowbe4.com/red-flags-warn-of-social-engineering"&gt;Know the Red Flags of Social Engineering&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Fox right" src="./../images/redflags.jpg" style="width: 3300px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walk on,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt; \`._,'/
 (_- -_)
   \o/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="fixmycomputer"/><category term="article"/><category term="tips"/><category term="basic"/><category term="recommended"/><category term="software"/><category term="password"/><category term="mfa"/><category term="backup"/><category term="patching"/><category term="productivity"/><category term="security"/></entry><entry><title>Intercept</title><link href="https://ineed.to/intercept/" rel="alternate"/><published>2010-03-30T16:40:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-20T19:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Bitpusher</name></author><id>tag:ineed.to,2010-03-30:/intercept/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Central Principle of JKD - Interception&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Header" src="./../images/fight-header.png" style="width: 1000px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The Central Principle: Interception is Integration&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens when an irresistible force meets an immovable object head-on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a better, or at least a more answerable, question: why should they meet head-on at all? And if an opponent's fist is substituted for the irresistible force, and your jaw for the immovable object, I bet you would agree they should never meet head on. The question then becomes, what are your options?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once such a force is on its way, there are fours:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do nothing: Let force meet obstacle – Passive response, passive result&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dodge the attack: Make force miss obstacle – Passive response, active result &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Block the attack: Stop force with force – Active response, passive result&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intercept the attack: Use all force to your advantage – Active response, active result&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have already ruled out the first option – there are obviously better, less personally damaging, ways of dealing with an attack than doing nothing…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such as the second option: dodge the attack. Not a bad idea. If you are about to get hit, move to where you won't get hit. It is quick, instinctive, and can be effective in avoiding injury. And it is "active" in that at the end of it you are in a new, potentially better, position. The fatal flaw: by itself, dodging an attack does not improve your circumstances for more than a few seconds. You are still on the defensive, and if you simply keep dodging, your moves are likely to be anticipated, or you will be backed into a corner. This makes refined variants of this technique, such as the "emergency response" and the bob-and-weave useful as secondary reactions – but not primary reactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third option could be better. Block your opponent's strike, neutralizing the attack. Use the "hard method" of the martial arts, meeting force with force. However, there are two obvious problems with this option: 1. If your force is not of the right type and in the right place, it may not be effective. 2. This response, like dodging, leaves you in "reactive" mode. You are still merely acting within the the environment dictated by your opponent and not controlling it. You deal with the force, but expend energy in doing so and may gain time, but not initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That leaves the fourth option: interception. The use of all force, including your opponent's force, to your own ends. In the domain of grappling, Judo and Jujitsu are known for this. The use of "ju" in each case is an explicit reference to the martial arts principle of the "soft method" – that of using your opponent's strength and energy against him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of interception came into its own in Jeet Kune Do, the non-traditional martial art created by Bruce Lee. As Bruce said in the first episode of "Longstreet"; "To reach me, you must move to me. Your attack offers me an opportunity to intercept you." That is the heart of Jeet Kune Do. As an attack approaches instead of simply moving out of the way or blocking (fundamentally passive moves), launch an attack of your own which cuts off your opponent's attack, turning the tables. Interception is the ultimate combination of "soft" and "hard" techniques, using both your opponent's force and your own to your advantage. This central principle of Jeet Kune Do makes it a great foundation for unarmed martial arts expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using all forces to your advantage, interception is the most complete, most whole, most integrated foundation of combat - "When an opponent expands, I contract. When he contracts, I expand. And when there is an opportunity, I do not hit; it hits all by itself." – Bruce Lee, “Enter the Dragon”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walk on,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt; \`._,'/
 (_- -_)
   \o/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="fight"/><category term="article"/><category term="jkd"/><category term="fight"/><category term="intercept"/><category term="martial"/></entry><entry><title>Warm-Up</title><link href="https://ineed.to/warm-up/" rel="alternate"/><published>2010-03-30T16:40:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-06-20T19:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Bitpusher</name></author><id>tag:ineed.to,2010-03-30:/warm-up/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Warm-up Exercises for Martial Arts&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Header" src="./../images/fight-header.png" style="width: 1000px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Warm-Up Exercises for Martial Training &amp;amp; Push Shuffle Drill Download&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A warm up should be performed before participating in technical sports, exercising, or stretching, and the martial arts are no exception. Warming up generally consists of a gradual increase in intensity of physical activity. This increase heart rate, increasing blood flow to your muscles, and raises your body temperature - which warms the muscles, making them more elastic and less susceptible to injury. It is important that warm ups should be specific to the exercise that will follow, which means that muscles used in the warm up are the muscles required for the following activity. In the case of martial arts training, where all muscles are being trained to react with speed and power, warming up all major muscle groups is desirable with a special emphasis on the feet and legs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Footwork is the foundation of martial arts, so proper warm-up and exercise of the legs and feet is essential. Here are several useful warm-up exercises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rocker Step:
1. Stand in the Bai Jong stance.
2. Push off the rear leg, land on the ball of your front foot.
3. Push off your front leg, and land on the ball of your rear foot.
Bouncing, or "rocking" back and forth like this, while not the sort of movement useful in actual combat, is a good warm-up for the legs and feet. Especially as moving on the balls of your feet, basic to combative footwork, is not naturally practiced when walking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jumping Jacks:
1. Stand with your feet together, arms at your sides.
2. Jump with both legs, spread them to about shoulder width, and land.
3. At the same time, swing your arms out and above your head.
4. Reverse the last two steps, returning to your original position.
Jumping Jacks warm up support muscles on the sides of your legs, and get shoulder muscles warmed up too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lunge Jumping Jacks:
Same as above, except as you jump bring one leg forward and one back so as to land in a lunge, and switching legs on the next jump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shadow Boxing:
1. Maintain good stance.
2. From the Rocker Step, throw first a single punch (e.g. Jab), then combinations of punches (e.g. Jab, Cross, Hook) as you move forward.
3. Increase the intensity and complexity of your combinations as you warm-up.
Since in Shadow Boxing you are starting to throw punches, the muscles you use to throw them are warmed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running in Place - Both with knees up to at least waist height, and with knees down kicking feet up behind.
When running in place, practice always keeping your arms up. That is where you will want them in a fight, so train with them there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jump Rope
Jumping rope is a great warm-up, and one that quickly transitions into a cardiovascular workout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Push Shuffle Drill
A specific part of Jeet Kune Do footwork is the Push Shuffle drill. The Push Shuffle drill warms up the leg muscles, exercises support muscles not much used in regular walking, and increases the speed and coordination of your footwork. In the Push Shuffle Drill, the instructor calls out a set of 2 to 4 cardinal directions (forward, back, left, right), and the student quickly executes Push Shuffles in each indicated direction. To facilitate solo practice the instructor's part has been recorded, so if you have an mp3 player with a "random" setting and a place to work out, you can do the Push Shuffle drill by yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ineed.to/warm-up/pushshufflewarmup.zip"&gt;Download instructions and mp3 files for the Push Shuffle Drill HERE.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warm-up exercises such as these will help to minimize your chance of injury, and maximize the benefits you get every time you train. After an initial warm up you can continue similar exercises at greater intensity levels for a cardiovascular workout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Train Hard - You Fight As You Train&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walk on,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt; \`._,'/
 (_- -_)
   \o/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="fight"/><category term="article"/><category term="jkd"/><category term="warmup"/><category term="exercise"/><category term="footwork"/><category term="solo"/></entry><entry><title>Winter Driving Tips</title><link href="https://ineed.to/winter-drive/" rel="alternate"/><published>2010-03-30T16:40:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-11-20T19:30:00-08:00</updated><author><name>Bitpusher</name></author><id>tag:ineed.to,2010-03-30:/winter-drive/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Winter Driving Tips&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Header" src="./../images/foxheader.png" style="width: 414px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The Snow Fox's Winter Driving Tips&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winter - A season of skiing, snowboarding, ice skating, and general icy, snowy, cold fun. But also a season of distinct driving challenges and hazards when traveling to and from such fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few tips to get you to the sites of such fun, and back again, safe and sound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When driving in snowy weather:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drive a full-time all-wheel drive vehicle if possible (each tire gets drive power). Next best is four wheel drive (in reality one front and one rear tire get power). Next best is front wheel drive (able to pull your vehicle along in snow, plus weight of engine is over tires for traction). Worst is rear wheel drive – especially a pickup truck.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you do have to drive a rear-wheel drive vehicle, make sure you have some weight in the back. A couple sandbags in the back of a pickup truck makes a huge difference in traction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carry and use proper chains/cables for your tires. Only use them on icy &amp;amp; snowy roads – they don't help on dry roads and are hard on the road. If you are spending the winter driving continuously on ice &amp;amp; snow, snow tires might be a good idea (check with your dealer).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small zip ties are great for tying off extra cable/chain links.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't use cruise control in bad weather – Your vehicles computer may not take road conditions into account when accelerating and braking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain momentum uphill – Keep steadily moving and don't stop if you don't have to. It is a lot easier to keep moving on snowy and icy roads than to start moving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ride your brakes downhill – Keep it slow so you stay in control and don't need to slam on the brakes. Going downhill a four wheel drive vehicle has no advantage over a two wheel drive one. It's all about gravity and braking traction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anti-lock brakes are nice, but if you don't have them you can get the same effect by pumping your brakes up and down instead of simply depressing them. To tell if you have them, push hard on your brakes on an empty, level straightaway (only if it is safe). If you feel a pulsing through the pedal, you have anti-lock brakes. Again, if you don't have anti-lock brakes, when you want to slow down fast on a bad road pump the brake pedal up and down to avoid them locking up &amp;amp; losing traction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you start to slide turn a bit INTO the slide direction and use a little gas. Don't brake - that will just make the slide worse. Getting the wheels moving with the direction of slide will help generate static friction (where each point of the tire is not moving in relation to where it is contacting the ground) and with static friction you can use your tires to pull/push you back on track.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't stop with one end of your vehicle in a downhill dead end – without gravity to help get you going it can be VERY hard to get out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you get stuck don't spin your tires – try rocking back and fourth, from drive to reverse, gradually gaining the momentum to get out of the depression.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carrying a tow strap is a good idea – They are cheap, and sometimes a little pull is all you need to get out of a slick spot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beware of shadows &amp;amp; bridges – Ice can linger in these areas long after it has melted everywhere else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lean over with your head against the drivers side window and adjust your driver side rear-view mirror so that from that position you can just barely see the side of your vehicle. Lean the same distance in the other direction and adjust the passenger side rear-view mirror the same way. If you did this right, there should now be a continuous field of vision from drivers side rear-view mirror to middle rear-view mirror to passenger side rear-view mirror, with very little overlap. It takes a little getting used to, but this panoramic arrangement almost eliminates blind spots!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A clean, raw potato can be used to prevent you windows from fogging. Cut it in half and rub the cut surface of the potato on the window. Leave to dry without touching.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sunglasses cut glare. Amber ones also improve contrast – good for when it's raining or snowing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spraying silicone lubricant around your door seals will keep them from freezing shut.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use isopropyl or rubbing alcohol to de-ice your windshield (alcohol has a lower freezing point than water). Don't use hot water to de-ice your windshield - The thermal shock may crack it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To speed defogging your windshield turn your car's heater on full-blast (hot air can hold more moisture), direct the air to the top vents flowing over the windshield, turn the A/C on (the AC's cooling coils pull more moisture out of the air), and turn air recalculation OFF (you want to get rid of humid air from inside the car and pull in colder, drier air from outside - then warm it so it picks up the moisture from the windows).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't neglect safety when out of your vehicle – A pair of Ice Cleats or other slip-on shoe traction systems really helps when walking on icy ground. Or just make your whole foot waterproof and grippy with a pair of Neos Overshoes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remember:&lt;/em&gt; driving in inclement weather is dangerous. Even if you are careful and do &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; right, you can still slide, hydroplane, hit black ice, or just get run into by the other guy. Don't drive in bad weather if it can be avoided. Don't drive in weather that you cannot handle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have fun. Drive safe.
"You always get experience after you need it."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ineed.to/winter-drive/WinterDrivingTips.pdf"&gt;Download these tips as a pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Fortuna eruditis favet."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walk on,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt; \`._,'/
 (_- -_)
   \o/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="prepare"/><category term="article"/><category term="driving"/><category term="winter"/><category term="tips"/><category term="safety"/><category term="snow"/></entry></feed>