<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>iNeed.to - fight</title><link href="https://ineed.to/" rel="alternate"/><link href="https://ineed.to/feeds/fight.atom.xml" rel="self"/><id>https://ineed.to/</id><updated>2025-07-20T19:30:00-07:00</updated><subtitle>Seeking the wholeness of the integrated person. Technology - Martial Arts - Learning</subtitle><entry><title>JKD Resources</title><link href="https://ineed.to/learn-jkd/" rel="alternate"/><published>2024-03-30T16:40:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-07-20T19:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Bitpusher</name></author><id>tag:ineed.to,2024-03-30:/learn-jkd/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Online resources for the martial art of Jeet Kune Do&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Header" src="./../images/fight-header.png" style="width: 1000px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Jeet Kune Do resources to learn from on the web&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Longstreet Episode 1 - Way of the Intercepting Fist&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=" position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;
&lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1_C6wKGL_ug" style="border: 1; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" title="Longstreet Episode 1 - Way of the Intercepting Fist (Bruce Lee)"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Return of the Dragon - Colosseum fight scene&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=" position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%;"&gt;
&lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kmgcqOM9rG0" style="border: 1; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; position: absolute;" title="Bruce Lee vs Chuck Norris - The Way of the Dragon (Return of the Dragon)"&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://jkdwednite.com/"&gt;The Wednesday Night Group - Original JKD passed on through one of the original groups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@jkdwng"&gt;JKD Wednesday Night Group YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/@jeremylynch8923"&gt;Jeet Kune Do Senior Instructor Jeremy Lynch's YouTube channel (with WNG podcast)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ineed.to/learn-jkd/JeremyLynch-OneInchOfPower.pdf"&gt;One Inch of Power - PDF eBook of exercises to improve the one inch punch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ineed.to/learn-jkd/JeremyLynch-JeetKuneDoBasics.pdf"&gt;Jeet Kune Do Basics - PDF eBook several fundamental JKD techniques&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walk on,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt; \`._,'/
 (_- -_)
   \o/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="fight"/><category term="article"/><category term="jkd"/><category term="resources"/><category term="longstreet"/><category term="punch"/><category term="ebook"/><category term="pdf"/><category term="download"/><category term="grow"/><category term="basics"/></entry><entry><title>Intercept</title><link href="https://ineed.to/intercept/" rel="alternate"/><published>2010-03-30T16:40:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-05-20T19:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Bitpusher</name></author><id>tag:ineed.to,2010-03-30:/intercept/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Central Principle of JKD - Interception&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Header" src="./../images/fight-header.png" style="width: 1000px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;The Central Principle: Interception is Integration&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens when an irresistible force meets an immovable object head-on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's a better, or at least a more answerable, question: why should they meet head-on at all? And if an opponent's fist is substituted for the irresistible force, and your jaw for the immovable object, I bet you would agree they should never meet head on. The question then becomes, what are your options?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once such a force is on its way, there are fours:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="mf"&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Do&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="ow"&gt;not&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;hing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kd"&gt;Let&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kr"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;ce&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;meet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;obstacle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;–&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Passive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;response&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;passive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;result&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="mf"&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Dodge&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;attack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Make&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kr"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;ce&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;miss&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;obstacle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;–&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Passive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;response&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;active&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;result&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="mf"&gt;3.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Block&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;attack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kr"&gt;Stop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kr"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;ce&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;with&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kr"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;ce&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;–&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Active&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;response&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;passive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;result&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="mf"&gt;4.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;Int&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;ercept&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;attack&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Use&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;all&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kr"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;ce&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kr"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;your&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;advantage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;–&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Active&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;response&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;active&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;result&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have already ruled out the first option – there are obviously better, less personally damaging, ways of dealing with an attack than doing nothing…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such as the second option: dodge the attack. Not a bad idea. If you are about to get hit, move to where you won't get hit. It is quick, instinctive, and can be effective in avoiding injury. And it is "active" in that at the end of it you are in a new, potentially better, position. The fatal flaw: by itself, dodging an attack does not improve your circumstances for more than a few seconds. You are still on the defensive, and if you simply keep dodging, your moves are likely to be anticipated, or you will be backed into a corner. This makes refined variants of this technique, such as the "emergency response" and the bob-and-weave useful as secondary reactions – but not primary reactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third option could be better. Block your opponent's strike, neutralizing the attack. Use the "hard method" of the martial arts, meeting force with force. However, there are two obvious problems with this option: 1. If your force is not of the right type and in the right place, it may not be effective. 2. This response, like dodging, leaves you in "reactive" mode. You are still merely acting within the the environment dictated by your opponent and not controlling it. You deal with the force, but expend energy in doing so and may gain time, but not initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That leaves the fourth option: interception. The use of all force, including your opponent's force, to your own ends. In the domain of grappling, Judo and Jujitsu are known for this. The use of "ju" in each case is an explicit reference to the martial arts principle of the "soft method" – that of using your opponent's strength and energy against him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of interception came into its own in Jeet Kune Do, the non-traditional martial art created by Bruce Lee. As Bruce said in the first episode of "Longstreet"; "To reach me, you must move to me. Your attack offers me an opportunity to intercept you." That is the heart of Jeet Kune Do. As an attack approaches instead of simply moving out of the way or blocking (fundamentally passive moves), launch an attack of your own which cuts off your opponent's attack, turning the tables. Interception is the ultimate combination of "soft" and "hard" techniques, using both your opponent's force and your own to your advantage. This central principle of Jeet Kune Do makes it a great foundation for unarmed martial arts expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using all forces to your advantage, interception is the most complete, most whole, most integrated foundation of combat - "When an opponent expands, I contract. When he contracts, I expand. And when there is an opportunity, I do not hit; it hits all by itself." – Bruce Lee, “Enter the Dragon”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walk on,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt; \`._,'/
 (_- -_)
   \o/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="fight"/><category term="article"/><category term="jkd"/><category term="fight"/><category term="intercept"/><category term="martial"/></entry><entry><title>Warm-Up</title><link href="https://ineed.to/warm-up/" rel="alternate"/><published>2010-03-30T16:40:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-06-20T19:30:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Bitpusher</name></author><id>tag:ineed.to,2010-03-30:/warm-up/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Summary of article&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Header" src="./../images/fight-header.png" style="width: 1000px; height: auto;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Warm-Up Exercises for Martial Training &amp;amp; Push Shuffle Drill Download&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A warm up should be performed before participating in technical sports, exercising, or stretching, and the martial arts are no exception. Warming up generally consists of a gradual increase in intensity of physical activity. This increase heart rate, increasing blood flow to your muscles, and raises your body temperature - which warms the muscles, making them more elastic and less susceptible to injury. It is important that warm ups should be specific to the exercise that will follow, which means that muscles used in the warm up are the muscles required for the following activity. In the case of martial arts training, where all muscles are being trained to react with speed and power, warming up all major muscle groups is desirable with a special emphasis on the feet and legs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Footwork is the foundation of martial arts, so proper warm-up and exercise of the legs and feet is essential. Here are several useful warm-up exercises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rocker Step:
1. Stand in the Bai Jong stance.
2. Push off the rear leg, land on the ball of your front foot.
3. Push off your front leg, and land on the ball of your rear foot.
Bouncing, or "rocking" back and forth like this, while not the sort of movement useful in actual combat, is a good warm-up for the legs and feet. Especially as moving on the balls of your feet, basic to combative footwork, is not naturally practiced when walking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jumping Jacks:
1. Stand with your feet together, arms at your sides.
2. Jump with both legs, spread them to about shoulder width, and land.
3. At the same time, swing your arms out and above your head.
4. Reverse the last two steps, returning to your original position.
Jumping Jacks warm up support muscles on the sides of your legs, and get shoulder muscles warmed up too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lunge Jumping Jacks:
Same as above, except as you jump bring one leg forward and one back so as to land in a lunge, and switching legs on the next jump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shadow Boxing:
1. Maintain good stance.
2. From the Rocker Step, throw first a single punch (e.g. Jab), then combinations of punches (e.g. Jab, Cross, Hook) as you move forward.
3. Increase the intensity and complexity of your combinations as you warm-up.
Since in Shadow Boxing you are starting to throw punches, the muscles you use to throw them are warmed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running in Place - Both with knees up to at least waist height, and with knees down kicking feet up behind.
When running in place, practice always keeping your arms up. That is where you will want them in a fight, so train with them there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jump Rope
Jumping rope is a great warm-up, and one that quickly transitions into a cardiovascular workout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Push Shuffle Drill
A specific part of Jeet Kune Do footwork is the Push Shuffle drill. The Push Shuffle drill warms up the leg muscles, exercises support muscles not much used in regular walking, and increases the speed and coordination of your footwork. In the Push Shuffle Drill, the instructor calls out a set of 2 to 4 cardinal directions (forward, back, left, right), and the student quickly executes Push Shuffles in each indicated direction. To facilitate solo practice the instructor's part has been recorded, so if you have an mp3 player with a "random" setting and a place to work out, you can do the Push Shuffle drill by yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ineed.to/warm-up/pushshufflewarmup.zip"&gt;Download instructions and mp3 files for the Push Shuffle Drill HERE.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warm-up exercises such as these will help to minimize your chance of injury, and maximize the benefits you get every time you train. After an initial warm up you can continue similar exercises at greater intensity levels for a cardiovascular workout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Train Hard - You Fight As You Train&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walk on,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt; \`._,'/
 (_- -_)
   \o/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="fight"/><category term="article"/><category term="jkd"/><category term="warmup"/><category term="exercise"/><category term="footwork"/><category term="solo"/></entry></feed>